<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: FAQ.xml,v 1.4 2012-03-22 10:42:29 mg Exp $ -->

<book lang="en">

<bookinfo>
<title>$Name</title>
<edition>$Description Version $Version</edition>

<copyright>
<year>$YearStamp</year>
<holder>$Vendor, $URL</holder>
</copyright>

<date>$DateStamp</date>

<legalnotice>
    <para>$License</para>
    <para>This work is copyrighted by $Vendor, Norsk-Data-Str. 1, 61352 Bad Homburg, Germany.</para>
    <para>Build Date: $DateStamp</para>
</legalnotice>

</bookinfo>

<preface id="preface">
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>The FAQ Module is an OTRS extension providing an FAQ or rather a knowledge database.</para>
    <para>It facilitates speeding-up the knowledge transfer between agents or (using a public web interface) between organizations and their customers, therefore effectively saving time.</para>
    <para>Please contact your commercial support (support@otrs.com) if you have any queries regarding this document or need further information.</para>
</preface>

<chapter>
    <title>Features</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ Explorer</title>
        <para>Intuitive navigation and flexible mapping of theme hierarchies within the FAQ Explorer enable easy navigation through the database.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>WYSIWYG Editor</title>
        <para>Using the WYSIWYG Editor you can change the formatting of articles and include screen shots or images.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ articles</title>
        <para>FAQ articles with various attributes like &quot;Symptom&quot;, &quot;Problem&quot;, &quot;Solution&quot;, &quot;Title&quot;, &quot;Language&quot;, &quot;Category&quot;, &quot;Keywords&quot;, &quot;State&quot;, &quot;Created&quot; and &quot;Changed&quot;.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ attachments</title>
        <para>You can add attachments to FAQ articles, which are available in the customer interface, too (e. g. user guides in pdf format).</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Agent and customer interfaces</title>
        <para>Using the FAQ state you can determine the interface(s), in which an FAQ article should be displayed. Articles with their state set to &quot;internal&quot; are only visible for agents via the Agent Interface; Articles whose state is set to &quot;external&quot; are also displayed in the protected customer section, and articles tagged as &quot;public&quot; are available in the non-protected public area as well.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Comfortable navigation / clickable keywords</title>
        <para>The key words feature enables comfortable navigation to alternative articles using clickable key words.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Linked objects</title>
        <para>FAQ articles can be linked to other objects such as tickets, FAQ articles or (CMDB) configuration items.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Full-text and quick search</title>
        <para>You can execute a full-text and quick search in the entire knowledge database. You can also use OTRS operators for &quot;AND&quot; or &quot;OR&quot; relations.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Top 10 articles</title>
        <para>An overview showing the Top 10 most often accessed, most recently generated and most recently changed articles.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Ranking / Voting of FAQ articles</title>
        <para>A personal ranking / voting of FAQ articles providing other users with information about the quality of FAQ articles.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Inserting FAQ articles in OTRS replies</title>
        <para>You can insert FAQ articles (without images) in replies you generate in OTRS.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Release workflow</title>
        <para>Workflow to release FAQ articles that have been newly generated or changed.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>RSS feeds for public FAQ articles</title>
        <para>In the public area, an option is provided to subscribe to RSS Feeds providing information about changes in FAQ articles.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>OpenSearch format</title>
        <para>The FAQ Module supports Open Search format (enabling quick searches directly from the browser).</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>System requirements</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Framework</title>
        <para>The following OTRS framework is required:</para>
        <para>
        $Framework
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Packages</title>
        <para>Following packages are required:</para>
        <para>
        $PackageRequired
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Operating system</title>
        <para>Following operating systems are to be considered as dependency:</para>
        <para>
        $OS
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Third party software</title>
        <para>Following software is required for package operation:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>None</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Installation</title>
    <para>The following instructions show how to install the package. Generally, there are two possibilities: You can either use the Admin Interface or the command line.</para>
    <para>After having successfully completed the installation, please follow the instructions provided in the chapter &quot;First steps&quot;.</para>
    <sect1>
        <title>Admin Interface</title>
        <para>
Using the following URL you can install, as well as update or uninstall (if necessary), the package via the Admin Interface (please check whether the user is a member of the Admin Group before starting.)
        </para>
        <para>
<ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager">http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager</ulink>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Command line</title>
        <para>
Whenever you cannot use the Admin Interface for whatever reason, you may use the following command line tool (&quot;bin/opm.pl&quot;) instead.
        </para>
        <para>
        <screen>
shell&gt; bin/opm.pl -a install -p /path/to/$Name-$Version.opm
        </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>First steps</title>
    <para>As soon as the FAQ Module has been installed, a group &quot;faq&quot; is automatically generated. Access to the FAQ Module is restricted to users with &quot;rw&quot; permission in this group.</para>
    <sect1>
        <title>Assigning the FAQ authorization</title>
        <para>Users with admin rights can add existing agents to the FAQ Group. For the change to be implemented, agents have to re-login after they have been added to the group. Afterwards, an &quot;FAQ&quot; symbol is displayed in their navigation area.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Creating categories</title>
        <para>First of all, you have to create FAQ categories.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Creating FAQ articles</title>
        <para>Then you can start creating new FAQ articles.</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Configuration</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Approval function</title>
    <para>The OTRS FAQ has an appoval feature. If you activate the approval feature all newly created FAQs also create
    a new ticket in a predefined queue. The persons who need to approve the FAQ entries can then act on these tickets and
    approve the FAQ articles if they see fit. As long as the article has not been approved the article will not be
    visible in the public interface.</para>
    <para>
    You can activate the Approval function by setting the option FAQ::ApprovalRequired to Yes.</para>
    <para>
    The approval message can be defined under FAQ::ApprovalTicketBody. You can modify the text if you need, and you can
    also use variables that will be substituted with their actual values when the approval note is generated. The list
    of the available variables is listed below.</para>
<table id="table-of-faq-approval-variables">
<title>Variables for FAQ Approval message</title>
  <tgroup cols="2">
    <thead>
      <row>
        <entry>
          Name
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Description
        </entry>
      </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_CATEGORY&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Category name of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_CATEGORYID&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Category ID of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_LANGUAGE&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Language of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_ITEMID&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Item ID of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_NUMBER&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          FAQ Number of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_TITLE&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Title
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_AUTHOR&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          Author name
        </entry>
      </row>
      <row>
        <entry>
          &lt;OTRS_FAQ_STATE&gt;
        </entry>
        <entry>
          State (visibility) of the FAQ article
        </entry>
      </row>
    </tbody>
  </tgroup>
</table>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>More Configuration Options</title>
    <para>There is a group &quot;FAQ&quot; in the Admin area of the SysConfig. Here you can find various configuration options for the FAQ module; most of them are self-explaining.</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Contact</title>
    <para>
Please direct questions about the FAQ Module at:
    </para>
    <sect1>
        <title>OTRS AG/OTRS Inc.</title>
        <para>
        E-mail: enjoy@otrs.com
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Change log</title>
    <para>
    $ChangeLog
    </para>
</chapter>


</book>
