<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<book lang="en">

<bookinfo>
<title>$Name</title>
<edition>$Description Version $Version</edition>

<copyright>
<year>$YearStamp</year>
<holder>$Vendor, $URL</holder>
</copyright>

<date>$DateStamp</date>

<legalnotice>
    <para>$License</para>
    <para>
        This work is copyrighted by $Vendor, Norsk-Data-Str. 1, 61352 Bad Homburg, Germany.
    </para>
    <para>
        Build Date: $DateStamp
    </para>
</legalnotice>

</bookinfo>

<preface id="preface">
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>
        The FAQ Module is an OTRS extension providing an FAQ or rather a knowledge database.
    </para>
    <para>
        It facilitates speeding-up the knowledge transfer between agents or (using a public web
        interface) between organizations and their customers, therefore effectively saving time.
    </para>
    <para>
        Please contact your commercial support (support@otrs.com) if you have any queries regarding
        this document or need further information.
    </para>
</preface>

<chapter>
    <title>Features</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ Explorer</title>
        <para>
            Intuitive navigation and flexible mapping of theme hierarchies within the FAQ Explorer
            enable easy navigation through the database.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>WYSIWYG Editor</title>
        <para>
            Using the WYSIWYG Editor you can change the formatting of articles and include screen
            shots or images.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ articles</title>
        <para>
            FAQ articles with various attributes like &quot;Symptom&quot;, &quot;Problem&quot;,
            &quot;Solution&quot;, &quot;Title&quot;, &quot;Language&quot;, &quot;Category&quot;,
            &quot;Keywords&quot;, &quot;State&quot;, &quot;Created&quot; and &quot;Changed&quot;
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>FAQ attachments</title>
        <para>
            You can add attachments to FAQ articles, which are available in the customer interface,
            too (e. g. user guides in pdf format).
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Agent and customer interfaces</title>
        <para>
            Using the FAQ state you can determine the interface(s), in which an FAQ article should
            be displayed. Articles with their state set to &quot;internal&quot; are only visible for
            agents via the Agent Interface; Articles whose state is set to &quot;external&quot; are
            also displayed in the protected customer section, and articles tagged as
            &quot;public&quot; are available in the non-protected public area as well.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Comfortable navigation / clickable keywords</title>
        <para>
            The key words feature enables comfortable navigation to alternative articles using
            clickable key words.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Linked objects</title>
        <para>
            FAQ articles can be linked to other objects such as tickets, FAQ articles or (CMDB)
            configuration items.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Full-text and quick search</title>
        <para>
            You can execute a full-text and quick search in the entire knowledge database. You can
            also use OTRS operators for &quot;AND&quot; or &quot;OR&quot; relations.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Top 10 articles</title>
        <para>
            An overview showing the Top 10 most often accessed, most recently generated and most
            recently changed articles.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Ranking / Voting of FAQ articles</title>
        <para>
            A personal ranking / voting of FAQ articles providing other users with information
            about the quality of FAQ articles.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Inserting FAQ articles in OTRS replies</title>
        <para>
            You can insert FAQ articles (without images) in replies you generate in OTRS.
         </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Release workflow</title>
        <para>
            Workflow to release FAQ articles that have been newly generated or changed.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>RSS feeds for public FAQ articles</title>
        <para>
            In the public area, an option is provided to subscribe to RSS Feeds providing
            information about changes in FAQ articles.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>OpenSearch format</title>
        <para>
            The FAQ Module supports Open Search format (enabling quick searches directly from the
            browser).
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Generic Interface FAQ connector for public interface</title>
        <para>
            Allow you to use the functions for FAQ public interface via OTRS Generic Interface.
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>System requirements</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Framework</title>
        <para>The following OTRS framework is required:</para>
        <para>
        $Framework
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Packages</title>
        <para>Following packages are required:</para>
        <para>
        $PackageRequired
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Operating system</title>
        <para>Following operating systems are to be considered as dependency:</para>
        <para>
        $OS
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Third party software</title>
        <para>Following software is required for package operation:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>None</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Installation</title>
    <para>
        The following instructions show how to install the package. Generally, there are two
        possibilities: You can either use the Admin Interface or the command line.
    </para>
    <para>
        After having successfully completed the installation, please follow the instructions
        provided in the chapter &quot;First steps&quot;.
    </para>
    <sect1>
        <title>Admin Interface</title>
        <para>
            Using the following URL you can install, as well as update or uninstall (if necessary),
            the package via the Admin Interface (please check whether the user is a member of the
            Admin Group before starting.)
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager
            </ulink>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Command line</title>
        <para>
            Whenever you cannot use the Admin Interface for whatever reason, you may use the
            following command line tool (&quot;bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl&quot;) instead.
        </para>
        <para>
        <screen>
shell> bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl -a install -p /path/to/$Name-$Version.opm
        </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>First steps</title>
    <para>
        As soon as the FAQ Module has been installed, a group &quot;faq&quot; is automatically
        generated. Access to the FAQ Module is restricted to users with &quot;rw&quot; permission
        in this group.
    </para>
    <sect1>
        <title>Assigning the FAQ authorization</title>
        <para>
            Users with admin rights can add existing agents to the FAQ Group. For the change to be
            implemented, agents have to re-login after they have been added to the group.
            Afterwards, an &quot;FAQ&quot; symbol is displayed in their navigation area.
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Creating categories</title>
        <para>First of all, you have to create FAQ categories.</para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>Creating FAQ articles</title>
        <para>Then you can start creating new FAQ articles.</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Configuration</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Approval function</title>
        <para>
            The OTRS FAQ has an approval feature. If you activate the approval feature all newly
            created FAQs also create a new ticket in a predefined queue. The persons who need to
            approve the FAQ entries can then act on these tickets and approve the FAQ articles if
            they see fit. As long as the article has not been approved the article will not be
            visible in the public interface.
        </para>
        <para>
            You can activate the Approval function by setting the option FAQ::ApprovalRequired to
            Yes.
        </para>
        <para>
            The approval message can be defined under FAQ::ApprovalTicketBody. You can modify the
            text if you need, and you can also use variables that will be substituted with their
            actual values when the approval note is generated. The list of the available variables
            is listed below.
        </para>
        <table id="table-of-faq-approval-variables">
        <title>Variables for FAQ Approval message</title>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <thead>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  Name
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Description
                </entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_CATEGORY&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Category name of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_CATEGORYID&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Category ID of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_LANGUAGE&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Language of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_ITEMID&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Item ID of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_NUMBER&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  FAQ Number of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_TITLE&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Title
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_AUTHOR&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  Author name
                </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  &lt;OTRS_FAQ_STATE&gt;
                </entry>
                <entry>
                  State (visibility) of the FAQ article
                </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>More Configuration Options</title>
        <para>
            There is a group &quot;FAQ&quot; in the Admin area of the SysConfig. Here you can find
            various configuration options for the FAQ module; most of them are self-explaining.
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Generic Interface FAQ connector</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Generic Interface for Public FAQ Data</title>
        <para>
            This package adds following Operations to the OTRS Generic Interface:
        </para>
        <sect2>
            <title>LanguageList</title>
            <para>
                This operation returns the list of all FAQ languages available in the system.
                The response of this operation is a list of languages including the ID and Name for
                each language.
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>PublicCategoryList</title>
            <para>
                This operation is used to get the system FAQ categories that have at least one
                public FAQ item, as a consequence also the category ancestors are also listed even
                if they don't have any public FAQ item. The output of this operation is a list of
                categories including ID and Name for each category.
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>PublicFAQSearch</title>
            <para>
                By using this operation is possible to perform a FAQ search for the public FAQ items
                using the same search parameters as in the public web interface. It will return a
                list of IDs for matched FAQ items.
            </para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2>
            <title>PublicFAQGet</title>
            <para>
                This operation can be used to easily obtain one or more FAQ items. The response will
                one or more main containers called 'FAQItem' that has all the FAQ item information,
                including attachments, each attachment is represented by an 'Attachment'
                sub-containers and they could be more than one.
            </para>
            <para>
                Please see the chapter "Generic Interface FAQ connector configuration" below for how
                to activate this feature, as well as chapter "Generic Interface FAQ connector API
                Reference" for details on using the above functions.
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Generic Interface FAQ connector configuration</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Web Service configuration</title>
        <para>
            In order to use the web service and the operations included on this package, you should
            first of all install the web service on your system, using the Command line or taking
            advantage of the Graphical User Interface (Admin Interface). Please note that the old
            configuration for rpc.pl is not relevant for the Generic Interface and therefore not
            needed.
        </para>
        <para>
            The following is an example of how to use Command line to install the web service in
            the system using the provided YAML file (.yaml) included on this package.
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
shell> $OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.WebserviceConfig.pl -a write -n GenericInterfaceFAQConnector -f $OTRS_HOME/scripts/webservices/GenericInterfaceFAQConnector.yaml
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Also you can install the web service importing the mentioned YAML file via web
            interface in the next URL using the 'Import web service' button on the left side bar.
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminGenericInterfaceWebservice;Subaction=Add">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminGenericInterfaceWebservice;Subaction=Add
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            The content of the YAML file is shown below.
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
---
Debugger:
  DebugThreshold: debug
  TestMode: 0
Description: ''
Provider:
  Operation:
    LanguageList:
      Description: List  all availables languages
      Type: FAQ::LanguageList
    PublicCategoryList:
      Description: List all public FAQ categories (with tree information)
      Type: FAQ::PublicCategoryList
    PublicFAQSearch:
      Description: Search for public FAQs
      Type: FAQ::PublicFAQSearch
    PublicFAQGet:
      Description: Retrieve public FAQ entries
      Type: FAQ::PublicFAQGet
  Transport:
    Config:
      Encoding: UTF-8
      Endpoint: ''
      MaxLength: 10000000
      NameSpace: http://www.otrs.org/FAQConnector/
      SOAPAction: ''
    Type: HTTP::SOAP
RemoteSystem: ''
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            In order to use the web service you need to use an new interface in OTRS.
            As for agents you use index.pl and for customers you use customer.pl, for web
            services you use <emphasis>nph-genericinterface.pl</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para>
            The default and suggested name for this web service is GenericFAQConnector.
            Since the name of the web service can be changed is very important that you write
            down the current name of your web service and update it in all locations that access
            to it.
        </para>
        <para>
            When a web service is installed on the system it always has an associated ID number.
            You can call the web service by name or by ID number. To get the list of
            <emphasis>valid</emphasis> web services and they corresponding ID number you can
            use the following command:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
shell> $OTRS_HOME/bin/otrs.WebserviceConfig.pl -a list
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            For this specific web service, using the default configuration you can call it as
            follows:
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/GenericFAQConnector">
                http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/Webservice/GenericFAQConnector
            </ulink>
            (by name, recommended) or
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/WebserviceID/1">
                http://localhost/otrs/nph-genericinterface.pl/WebserviceID/1
            </ulink>
            (by ID).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Note:</emphasis> both web service name and ID from the example above could
            be different in your current environment.
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>New ways to create links</title>
    <sect1>
        <title>Create links using the category name</title>
        <para>
            It is now possible to refer to FAQ items by creating a link for web browser using the
            category name instead of just the category ID
        </para>
        <para>
            To be able to use this feature just replace the CategoryID parameter with Category
            parameter in your current links. Category parameter is the full category path, each
            sub-category is separated by "::" (which is also called the "Category Long Name").
            Imagine the following category tree:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
GrandParent
    Parent
        Son
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            To create a link to the "Son" category we need to specify the following path:
            Category=GrandParent::Parent::Son.
        </para>
        <para>
            See the link examples below:
        </para>
        <para>
            from:
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;CategoryID=1">
                    http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;CategoryID=1
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            to:
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;Category=Misc">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;Category=Misc
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            Other Examples:
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;Category=My%20Category">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminFAQExplorer;Category=My%20Category
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=CustomerFAQExplorer;Category=GranParent::Parent::Son">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=CustomerFAQExplorer;Category=GrandParent::Parent::Son
            </ulink>
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=PublicFAQExplorer;Category=My%20Category::SubCategory">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=PublicFAQExplorer;Category=My%20Category::Subcategory
            </ulink>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Generic Interface FAQ connector API</title>
    <para>
        For the following examples uses SOAP XML data structures since HTTP::SOAP is the default
        transport for Generic Interface Operations and can be used with otrs.SOAPRequest.pl.
    </para>
    <para>
        otrs.SOAPRequest.pl is a simple Perl script to test the OTRS Generic Interface, the code
        can be found in the OTRS administration manual.
    </para>
    <sect1>
        <title>LanguageList</title>
        <para>
            For this operation is not necessary to send any special parameter to the server, you
            just need to request the web service directly indicating the "LanguageList" operation.
            The operation will return a list of languages including ID and the Name for each
            language on the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            Request format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
        <LanguageList/>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <LanguageListResponse>
         <!--1 or more repetitions:-->
         <Language>
            <ID>?</ID>
            <Name>?</Name>
         </Language>
      </LanguageListResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <LanguageListResponse>
         <Language>
            <ID>1</ID>
            <Name>en</Name>
         </Language>
         <Language>
            <ID>2</ID>
            <Name>de</Name>
         </Language>
         <Language>
            <ID>3</ID>
            <Name>es</Name>
         </Language>
      </LanguageListResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>PubliCcategoryList</title>
        <para>
            For this operation is also not necessary any special parameter, just the simple call for
            requesting the web service with the operation name 'PublicCategoryList' as a response
            you will receive a list of categories including the ID and the Name (long format) for
            each category.
        </para>
        <para>
            Request format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
        <PublicCategoryList/>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
     <PublicCategoryListResponse>
         <!--1 or more repetitions:-->
         <Category>
            <ID>?</ID>
            <Name>?</Name>
         </Category>
      </PublicCategoryListResponse>
                 ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicCategoryListResponse>
         <Category>
            <ID>2</ID>
            <Name>Pulbic</Name>
         </Category>
         <Category>
            <ID>5</ID>
            <Name>Public::SubCategory A</Name>
         </Category>
         <Category>
            <ID>8</ID>
            <Name>Public::SubCategory B</Name>
         </Category>
      </PublicCategoryListResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>PublicFAQGet</title>
        <para>
            To be able to get one or more FAQ entries, you should send the ItemID(s) as a parameter
            for the FAQ entry you want to get. You will receive the entire FAQ record with all
            attachments included if any. Note that attachments will be transferred as base64-encoded
            strings.
        </para>
        <para>
            Request format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQGet>
         <ItemID>?</ItemID>
      </PublicFAQGet>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Request example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQGet>
        <ItemID>6,7</ItemID>
      </PublicFAQGet>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQGetResponse>
         <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
         <FAQItem>
            <Approved>?</Approved>
            <CategoryID>?</CategoryID>
            <CategoryName>?</CategoryName>
            <CategoryShortName>?</CategoryShortName>
            <Changed>?</Changed>
            <ChangedBy>?</ChangedBy>
            <Created>?</Created>
            <CreatedBy>?</CreatedBy>
            <FAQID>?</FAQID>
            <Field1>?</Field1>
            <Field2>?</Field2>
            <Field3>?</Field3>
            <Field4>?</Field4>
            <Field5>?</Field5>
            <Field6>?</Field6>
            <ID>?</ID>
            <ItemID>?</ItemID>
            <Keywords>?</Keywords>
            <Language>?</Language>
            <LanguageID>?</LanguageID>
            <Name>?</Name>
            <Number>?</Number>
            <State>?</State>
            <StateID>?</StateID>
            <StateTypeID>?</StateTypeID>
            <Title>?</Title>
            <VoteResult>?</VoteResult>
            <Votes>?</Votes>
            <StateTypeName>?</StateTypeName>
            <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
            <Attachment>
               <Filename>?</Filename>
               <Filesize>?</Filesize>
               <ContentType>?</ContentType>
               <Content>cid:1269416154096</Content>
            </Attachment>
         </FAQItem>
      </PublicFAQGetResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQGetResponse>
          <FAQItem>
            <ID>6</ID>
            <ItemID>6</ItemID>
            <FAQID>6</FAQID>
            <Number>10006</Number>
            <CategoryID>2</CategoryID>
            <CategoryName>Public</CategoryName>
            <CategoryShortName>Public</CategoryShortName>
            <LanguageID>1</LanguageID>
            <Language>en</Language>
            <Title>Public2</Title>
            <Field1>The Symptoms</Field1>
            <Field2>The Problem</Field2>
            <Field3>The Solution</Field3>
            <Field4/>
            <Field5/>
            <Field6>The Comments</Field6>
            <Approved>1</Approved>
            <Keywords>Keyword1 Keyword2 Keyword3</Keywords>
            <Votes>1</Votes>
            <VoteResult>75.00</VoteResult>
            <StateID>3</StateID>
            <State>public (all)</State>
            <StateTypeID>3</StateTypeID>
            <StateTypeName>public</StateTypeName>
            <Created>2010-11-02 08:06:43</Created>
            <CreatedBy>1</CreatedBy>
            <Changed>2010-11-02 08:06:43</Changed>
            <ChangedBy>1</ChangedBy>
            <Name>1288706803-91.878184450707</Name>
             <Attachment>
                <Content>...==</Content>
                <ContentType>text/plain</ContentType>
                <Filename>Details.txt</Filename>
                <Filesize>296</Filesize>
             </Attachment>
             <Attachment>
                <Content>...==</Content>
                <ContentType>text/plain</ContentType>
                <Filename>Text.bin</Filename>
                <Filesize>980</Filesize>
             </Attachment>
          </FAQItem>
          <FAQItem>
            <ID>7</ID>
            <ItemID>7</ItemID>
            <FAQID>7</FAQID>
            <Number>10006</Number>
            <CategoryID>2</CategoryID>
            <CategoryName>Public</CategoryName>
            <CategoryShortName>Public</CategoryShortName>
            <LanguageID>1</LanguageID>
            <Language>en</Language>
            <Title>Public777</Title>
            <Field1>The Symptoms</Field1>
            <Field2>The Problem</Field2>
            <Field3>The Solution</Field3>
            <Field4/>
            <Field5/>
            <Field6>The Comments</Field6>
            <Approved>1</Approved>
            <Keywords>Keyword1 Keyword2 Keyword3</Keywords>
            <Votes>1</Votes>
            <VoteResult>75.00</VoteResult>
            <StateID>3</StateID>
            <State>public (all)</State>
            <StateTypeID>3</StateTypeID>
            <StateTypeName>public</StateTypeName>
            <Created>2010-16-03 02:06:43</Created>
            <CreatedBy>1</CreatedBy>
            <Changed>2010-11-02 02:06:43</Changed>
            <ChangedBy>1</ChangedBy>
            <Name>1288706803-91.878184450707</Name>
          </FAQItem>
      </PublicFAQGetResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
    <sect1>
        <title>PublicFAQSearch</title>
        <para>
            For this operation you can specify the following optional parameters: Name, Title, What
            (full text search), Keyword, LanguageIDs and CategoryIDs to narrow the search results.
            You may also specify the order of the results by the following parameters: OrderBy and
            OrderByDirection.
        </para>
        <para>
            Send a request to the web service with the operation name 'PublicFAQSearch' as a
            response you will receive a list of FAQ item IDs.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emphasis>Note: </emphasis>
            The full FAQ item data can be retrieved for each ID by using 'PublicFAQGet' operation
            separately.
        </para>
        <para>
            Request format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQSearch>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <Number>?</Number>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <Title>?</Title>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <What>?</What>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <Keyword>?</Keyword>
         <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
         <LanguageIDs>?</LanguageIDs>
         <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
         <CategoryIDs>?</CategoryIDs>
         <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
         <SortBy>?</SortBy>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <OrderBy>?</OrderBy>
         <!--Optional:-->
         <OprderByDirection>?</OprderByDirection>
      </PublicFAQSearch>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Request example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
     <PublicFAQSearch>
        <Number>*134*</Number>
        <Title>*some title*</Title>
        <What>*some text*</What>
        <Keyword>*webserver*</Keyword/>
        <LanguageIDs>1</LanguageIDs>
        <CategoryIDs>2</CategoryIDs>
        <OrderBy>FAQID</OrderBy>
        <OrderByDirection>Up</OrderByDirection>
      </PublicFAQSearch>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response format:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQSearchResponse>
         <!--Zero or more repetitions:-->
         <ID>?</ID>
      </PublicFAQSearchResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Response example:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                <![CDATA[
      <PublicFAQSearchResponse>
         <ID>20</ID>
         <ID>19</ID>
         <ID>18</ID>
         <ID>17</ID>
         <ID>16</ID>
         <ID>15</ID>
         <ID>14</ID>
         <ID>13</ID>
         <ID>11</ID>
         <ID>6</ID>
         <ID>5</ID>
      </PublicFAQSearchResponse>
                ]]>
            </screen>
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Contact</title>
    <para>
        Please direct questions about the FAQ Module at:
    </para>
    <sect1>
        <title>OTRS AG/OTRS Inc.</title>
        <para>
            E-mail: enjoy@otrs.com
        </para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <title>Change log</title>
    <para>
        $ChangeLog
    </para>
</chapter>

</book>
