<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">

<book lang='en'>

<!-- ************************************** Head *********************************************** -->

<bookinfo>
<title>$Name</title>
<edition>$Description Version $Version</edition>

<copyright>
<year>$YearStamp</year>
<holder>$Vendor, $URL</holder>
</copyright>

<date>$DateStamp</date>

<legalnotice>
    <para>$License</para>
    <para>This work is copyrighted by $Vendor, Norsk-Data-Str. 1, 61352 Bad Homburg, Germany.</para>
    <para>Build Date: $DateStamp</para>
</legalnotice>

</bookinfo>

<!-- ************************************ Customer part ****************************************** -->

<preface id="preface" >
    <!-- ********** -->
    <!-- 1. Preface -->
    <!-- ********** -->
    <title>Preface</title>
    <para>
        Adds the functionality to create Surveys that customers of closed tickets are invited to take part.
    </para>
    <para>
        Shows graphical statistics of completed Surveys.
    </para>
</preface>

<chapter>
    <!-- *************** -->
    <!-- 2. Feature List -->
    <!-- *************** -->
    <title>Feature List</title>
    <para>This Module enables you to create new Surveys,
        add questions to a created Survey, set a Survey live in order to send
        requests, modify existing Surveys to a certain extent,
        and view statistics of submitted Survey answers as well as the answers
        themselves.
    </para>
</chapter>
<chapter>
    <!-- ******************** -->
    <!-- 3. System Reqirement -->
    <!-- ******************** -->
    <title>System Requirement</title>
    <section>
        <title>Framework</title>
        <para>The following OTRS framework is required:</para>
        <para>
        $Framework
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Packages</title>
        <para>The following package are required:</para>
        <para>
        $PackageRequired
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Operating System</title>
        <para>This package requires one of the following operating systems:</para>
        <para>
        $OS
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Third Party Software</title>
        <para>This third party software is required to use this package:</para>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>None.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- *************** -->
    <!-- 4. Installation -->
    <!-- *************** -->
    <title>Installation</title>
    <para>The following instructions explain how to install the package.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Admin Interface</title>
        <para>
            Please use the following URL to install the package utilizing the admin
            interface (please note that you need to be in the admin group).
        </para>
        <para>
            <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager">
                http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager
            </ulink>
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Command Line</title>
        <para>
            Whenever you cannot use the Admin Interface for whatever reason,
            you may use the following command line tool (&quot;bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl&quot;)
            instead.
        </para>
        <para>
        <screen>
            shell> bin/otrs.PackageManager.pl  -a install -p /path/to/$Name-$Version.opm
        </screen>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- **************** -->
    <!-- 5. Configuration -->
    <!-- **************** -->
    <title>Configuration</title>
    <para>
        The following list of configuration options can be changed for this package.
    </para>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::ShowVoteData</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            Shows vote results to customers if set to Yes.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::SendPeriod</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            Avoids spamming customers with Survey requests.
            The number given here is the amount of days,
            a customer won't get a second Survey request
            after having received a request. In this
            time periode tickets for this customer
            can be closed without triggering new
            Survey requests.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::NotificationSender</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            The sender adress that is proposed
            on creation of new Surveys.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::NotificationRecipientBlacklist</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            Mailadresses that will never get Survey requests.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::NotificationSubject</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            The NotificationSubject that is proposed
            on creation of new Surveys.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::NotificationBody</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            The NotificationBody that is proposed
            on creation of new Surveys.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::SendNoSurveyRegExp</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Core</para>
        <para>
            If this regex matches, no customer Survey will be sent.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey::Frontend::AgentSurvey###ShowColumns</title>
        <para>Group: Survey, Subgroup: Frontend::Agent::SurveyOverview</para>
        <para>
            Defines the shown columns in the Survey overview.
            This option has no effect on the position of the column.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- ******** -->
    <!-- 6. Usage -->
    <!-- ******** -->
    <title>Usage</title>
    <section>
        <title>Create new Survey</title>
        <para>
            This feature lets OTRS users create new Survey by selecting the menu "SURVEY"
            and choosing "New".
        </para>
        <para>
            New Surveys require a title, an introduction text, a sender mail address, a mail subject,
            a mail body and an internal description of the Survey.
        </para>
        <para>
            Additionally the new Survey can be created for just some queues.
            If none are selected, it will be valid for every Queue.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Add Questions</title>
        <para>
            As soon as a new Survey is created, the user can add questions to this Survey by clicking
            "Edit Questions" in the displayed Survey.
        </para>
        <para>
            A new window will pop up. In there the user can add questions.
        </para>
        <para>
            Four types of questions are selectable. These are:
        </para>
        <para>
            "YesNo" questions a user can answer by selecting "Yes" or "No" of a drop down select.
        </para>
        <para>
            "Radio (List)" questions a user can answer by selecting exactly one and just one of the possible answers.
        </para>
        <para>
            "Checkbox (List)" questions a user can answer by selecting none to all listed answers.
        </para>
        <para>
            "Textarea" questions a user can write answers by typing regular text.
        </para>
        <para>
            For each answer type the OTRS user can choose
            if he wants a customer to be required to answer this question or if a customer can ignore the question.
        </para>
        <para>
            As soon as questions of type "Radio (List)" or "Checkbox (List)" got added,
            the question will be shown in the "Survey Questions"-List.
            By clicking on the question the user can add answers,
            change the answer order by clicking the "UP" or "DOWN" icon,
            or delete the answer by clicking the "DELETE" icon.
        </para>
        <para>
            Questions of type "Radio (List)" or "Checkbox (List)"
            need to have at least two answers to be valid.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Start sending Survey requests</title>
        <para>
            When the OTRS user has finished adding or modifying questions and possible answers,
            he can leave the "Edit Questions" area by clicking "Close window".
        </para>
        <para>
            Back on the Survey detail page the user can select "Master" from the
            "- Change Status -" select.
        </para>
        <para>
            As soon as the Survey has the state "Master" the Survey is set live.
        </para>
        <para>
            Only one Survey can have the state "Master".
        </para>
        <para>
            If a Ticket got closed, the customer gets an E-Mail invitation to fill the Survey
            by clicking a link inside the invitation E-Mail.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Survey Results Graph</title>
        <para>
            By selecting "SURVEY" from the menu, choosing "Overview", clicking on a
            a Survey that customers already submitted and scrolling down,
            you can see the "Survey Results Graph".
        </para>
        <para>
            This displays the statistically summarizeable questions (e.g. YesNo, Radio and Checkbox).
        </para>
        <para>
            As soon as the Survey has the state "Master" the Survey is set live.
        </para>
        <para>
            Questions where answers were configured as "required" will have
            one vote for each customer submitted Survey.
        </para>
        <para>
            Questions where answers were not configured as "required"
            are optional for the customer. This means that for example 200 customers submitted
            the Survey but in the statistic in total only 10 or 20 answers may occur, if
            customers did not select any of the Radio (List), YesNo or checkbox answers
            or haven't put anything in a textarea answer.
        </para>
        <para>
            Statistics for required Checkbox (List) questions will have at least one
            checked value for every submitted Survey but due to it's nature of beeing
            multiple clickable there may be more answers than the total amount of submitted
            Surveys. Examlpe: 200 Surveys submitted by customers, 350 answers on one
            Checkbox (List) question.
        </para>
        <para>
            Statistics for not required questions may have
            less votes than the total amount of submitted Surveys (answer is optional).
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Stats Details</title>
        <para>
            By selecting "SURVEY" from the menu, choosing "Overview", clicking on a
            Survey that customers already submitted and choosing "Stats Details"
            you can see a list containing the time the Survey invitation was sent to the customer,
            the time the customer submitted his filled Survey, the Ticket (clickable)
            and a magnifying glass that shows the selected votes for this customer.
        </para>
        <para>
            In there you can find the answers the customer chose or typed in question by question.
        </para>
        <para>
            Especially Textarea answers are of interest in here.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Modifying Survey</title>
        <para>
            As soon as a Survey had the Status "Master" the possible modifications are limited.
            So please make sure to have especially the amount of questions as well as
            the amount of answers correctly configured before changing it's status
            to Master.
        </para>
        <para>
            WARNING: In a Survey of type "Master" you can not add or delete questions any more.
        </para>
        <para>
            In a Survey of type Master you can change the general info
            (e.g. Title, Introduction, Sender,...), the question text,
            the answer text, as well as the order of the answers.
        </para>
        <para>
            You can change the "Answer Required" part of a question too,
            but this may just make sense as long as there are no
            submitted customer Surveys.
        </para>
        <para>
            Changing a "Answer Required" Question to answer not required
            makes the answer optional, so the statistic for this question may
            not have an answer for each submitted customer Survey
            any more.
        </para>
        <para>
            Changing a "Answer not Required" Question to answer required
            will require future Survey customers to give a vote for
            this question, but will not add votes for already submitted
            Surveys. So statistics will render rather usless too.
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<!-- ***************************************** Technical part ************************************ -->

<chapter>
    <!-- ********************************* -->
    <!-- 7. Technical Implematation Detail -->
    <!-- ********************************* -->
    <title>Technical Implementation Details</title>
    <para>
        This module adds the following database tables:
        survey,
        survey_answer,
        survey_question,
        survey_queue,
        survey_request,
        survey_vote.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey table holds the general information of a survey.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey_answer holds the answers for a survey questions.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey_question holds all question related information as well as if an answer is required or not.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey_queue table holds a record for each queue a survey is added.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey_request table holds a record for each request sent to a customer,
        as well as the time, a customer has submitted the survey he was invited to.
    </para>
    <para>
        The survey_vote table holds a reference to the corresponding request and question
        as well as the chosen answers.
    </para>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- *********** -->
    <!-- 8. Filelist -->
    <!-- *********** -->
    <title>Filelist</title>
    <!-- Standard text. Don't change this -->
    <para>This list shows all included files and the referring permissions.</para>
    <para>
       $Filelist
    </para>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- ******* -->
    <!-- 9. Test -->
    <!-- ******* -->
    <title>Tests</title>
    <para>This module has been tested on the current state of the art in quality.</para>
    <section>
        <title>Testcases</title>
        <para>
            To tests this package please follow the examples described in the Usage section, all the
            tests cases should return the expected results defined at the beginning of each example.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Unitest</title>
        <para>
            To ensure the quality of the module, several so-called unit tests were created, to test
            the functionalities of this module. These unit tests can be run via command line.
        </para>
        <para>
            ATTENTION: Please never run unit tests on a productive system, since the added test
            data to the system will no longer be removed. Always use a test system.
        </para>
        <para>
            Run the package specific unit tests
        </para>
        <para>
            To run only the unit test which will be delivered with this package, use the following
            command on the command line:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                shell> perl bin/otrs.UnitTest.pl -n DynamicTicketTemplate
            </screen>
        </para>
        <para>
            Run all available unit tests
        </para>
        <para>
            To run all available unit tests, use the following command on the command line:
        </para>
        <para>
            <screen>
                shell> perl bin/otrs.UnitTest.pl
            </screen>
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- ************* -->
    <!-- 10. Changelog -->
    <!-- ************* -->
    <title>ChangeLog</title>
    <para>
    $ChangeLog
    </para>
</chapter>

<chapter>
    <!-- *********** -->
    <!-- 11. Contact -->
    <!-- *********** -->
    <title>Contacts</title>
    <para>People who are involved in this implementation.</para>
    <section>
        <title>OTRS AG</title>
        <para>
            Accounting: xxxx xxxxx &lt;sales@otrs.com&gt;, Phone +49 (0)6172 681988 0
        </para>
        <para>
            Technical: xxxxxxxxx xxxxxxxxx &lt;dev-support@otrs.com&gt;, Phone +49 (0)6172 681988 0
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>

</book>
