<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<!-- $Id: SystemMonitoring.xml,v 1.2 2010-11-15 20:46:05 mb Exp $ -->
<book lang="en">
    <bookinfo>
        <title>$Name</title>
        <edition>$Description Version $Version</edition>
        <copyright>
            <year>$YearStamp</year>
            <holder>$Vendor, $URL</holder>
        </copyright>
        <date>$DateStamp</date>
        <legalnotice>
            <para>$License</para>
            <para>This work is copyrighted by $Vendor, Norsk-Data-Str. 1, 61352 Bad Homburg, Germany.</para>
            <para>Build Date: $DateStamp</para>
        </legalnotice>
    </bookinfo>
    <preface id="preface">
        <title>Preface</title>
        <para>This module implements a basic interface to System Monitoring Suites. It
    works by receiving email messages sent by a Network Monitoring Suite. New
    tickets are created in case of component failures. Once a ticket has
    been opened messages regarding the effected component are attached to
    this ticket. When the component recovers, the ticket state can be
    changed or the ticket can be closed.
</para>
        <para>If an open ticket for a given Host/Service combination exists, all
    mails concerning this particular combination will be attached to the
    ticket until it's closed.
</para>
        <para>Please contact your commercial support (support@otrs.com) if you have any queries regarding this document or need further information.</para>
    </preface>
    <chapter>
        <title>Control flow</title>
        <para>The following diagram illustrates how mails are handled by this module
    and in which cases they trigger which action. Pretty much all checks are
    configurable using the regular expressions given by the parameters listed
    above.
</para>
            <screen><![CDATA[
Mail matches 'FromAddress'?
|
+-> NO  --> Continue with regular mail processing
|
+-> YES --> Does a ticket with matching Host/Service combination
            already exist in OTRS?
            |
            +-> NO  -> Does 'State:' match 'NewTicketRegExp'?
            |          |
            |          +-> NO  -> Stop processing this mail
            |          |          (silent drop)
            |          |
            |          +-> YES -> Create new ticket, record Host
            |                     and Service, attach mail
            |
            +-> YES -> Attach mail to ticket
                    -> Does 'State:' match 'CloseTicketRegExp'?
                        |
                        +-> NO  -> Continue with regular mail processing
                        |
                        +-> YES -> Change ticket type as configured in
                                    'CloseActionState']]>
</screen>
<para>Besides of a few additional sanity checks this is how the
    SystemMonitoring module treats incoming mails. By changing the regular
    expressions it should be possible to adopt it to different monitoring
    systems.
</para>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>System requirements</title>
        <sect1>
            <title>Framework</title>
            <para>The following OTRS framework is required:</para>
            <para>
        $Framework
        </para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>Packages</title>
            <para>Following packages are required:</para>
            <para>
        $PackageRequired
        </para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>Operating system</title>
            <para>Following operating systems are to be considered as dependency:</para>
            <para>
        $OS
        </para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>Third party software</title>
            <para>Following software is required for package operation:</para>
            <para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem>
                        <para>A network monitoring system, such as Nagios, or HP OpenView, or similar, capable of sending out events via e-mail.</para>
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </sect1>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Installation</title>
        <para>The following instructions show how to install the package. Generally, there are two possibilities: You can either use the Admin Interface or the command line.</para>
        <para>After having successfully completed the installation, please follow the instructions provided in the chapter "First steps".</para>
        <sect1>
            <title>Admin Interface</title>
            <para>
Using the following URL you can install, as well as update or uninstall (if necessary), the package via the Admin Interface (please check whether the user is a member of the Admin Group before starting.)
        </para>
            <para>
                <ulink url="http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager">http://localhost/otrs/index.pl?Action=AdminPackageManager</ulink>
            </para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>Command line</title>
            <para>
Whenever you cannot use the Admin Interface for whatever reason, you may use the following command line tool ("bin/opm.pl") instead.
        </para>
            <para>
                <screen format="linespecific">
shell> bin/opm.pl -a install -p /path/to/$Name-$Version.opm
        </screen>
            </para>
        </sect1>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Configuration</title>
        <para>To allow flexible integration between OTRS and a System Monitoring Suite
    the following configuration options are available. The default values
    (as shown below) should be suitable for a standard Nagios installation.
    </para>
        <sect1>
            <title>FromAddressRegExp</title>
            <para>Only mails matching this "From:" address will be considered for this
        filter. You need to adjust this setting to the from address your
        System Monitoring Suite uses for outgoing mails.</para>
            <para>Default: 'sysmon@mysystem.com'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>StateRegExp</title>
            <para>Regular Expression to extract the state from the message.</para>
            <para>Default: '\s*State:\s+(\S+)'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>NewTicketRegExp</title>
            <para>Regular expression for extracted state to trigger a new ticket</para>
            <para>Default: 'CRITICAL|DOWN'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>CloseTicketRegExp</title>
            <para>Regular expression for extracted "State" to trigger ticket
        transition to "CloseActionState".</para>
            <para>Default: 'OK|UP'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>CloseActionState</title>
            <para>New status for ticket when service recovers. This can be either
        "OLD" in which case the old status stays, or the name of the new
        status. Please note, that this state needs to be configured in your
        OTRS installation as valid state. If the state you set here does not
        exist, the ticket state will not be altered.</para>
            <para>Default: 'closed successful'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>ClosePendingTime</title>
            <para>Pending time in seconds for 'Pending...' statuses. (Ignored for
        other status types). Please note that this setting will be ignored
        by OTRS versions older than 2.2. On these systems the pending time
        already associated with the ticket will be used, which may have in
        surprising effects. It's recommended not to use 'Pending...' states
        with OTRS prior to 2.2.</para>
            <para>Default: '60*60*24*2' (2 days)</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>HostRegExp</title>
            <para>Regular expression to extract the affected host.</para>
            <para>Default: '\s*Address:\s+(\d+\.\d+\.\d+\.\d+)\s*'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>FreeTextHost</title>
            <para>Free text field index to store the name of the affected host.</para>
            <para>Default: '1'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>ServiceRegExp</title>
            <para>Regular expression to extract the affected service.</para>
            <para>Default: '\s*Service:\s+(.*)\s*'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>DefaultService</title>
            <para>Default for "Service"; used if no service can be extracted, i.e. if
        host goes DOWN/UP.</para>
            <para>Default: 'Host'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>FreeTexyService</title>
            <para> Free text field index to store service.</para>
            <para>Default: '2'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>SenderType</title>
            <para>Sender type used for creating tickets and attaching notes.</para>
            <para>Default: 'system'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>ArticleType</title>
            <para>Article type used to attach follow up emails to existing tickets.</para>
            <para>Default: 'note-report'</para>
        </sect1>
        <sect1>
            <title>Integration with OTRS Configuration Management</title>
            <para>If the OTRS::ITSM Configuration Management module is installed and
    the configuration option 'SystemMonitoring::SetIncidentState' is set
    to 'Yes', a CI with the given host name is searched in the CI database.
    If exactly one CI with this name was found, the current incident state is set
    automatically according to the incoming mail (Incident / Operational).

    If the OTRS::ITSM Configuration Management module is installed and
    the configuration option 'SystemMonitoring::LinkTicketWithCI' is set
    to 'Yes', a CI is linked automatically with the system monitoring
    incident ticket. This is only possible if a subsequent system monitoring
    email arrives!
</para></sect1>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Contact</title>
        <para>
Please direct questions about the $Name Module to:
    </para>
        <sect1>
            <title>OTRS AG/OTRS Inc.</title>
            <para>
        E-mail: enjoy@otrs.com
        </para>
        </sect1>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Change log</title>
        <para>
    $ChangeLog
    </para>
    </chapter>
</book>
